[Music]
thank you
good morning everyone how's it going
today welcome to this week's new video
tutorial on software development and
artificial intelligence in this video
we're going to be building a complete
application with a graphical user
interface all of it coded in Python okay
the application deals with some with the
data set then trains a machine learning
algorithm and displays some predictions
based on the input data as well as some
chart to visualize the data as well okay
so by the end of this video you will
have this application that you will be
able to put in your portfolio and show
it to potential employers and to your
friends as well
so let me show you just real quick how
this works you have a you have a sidebar
right here with a lot of inputs and the
inputs are are represented in a chart
right here so if I change something like
here you will see that my chart changes
okay and also in real time we are making
a prediction using the logistic
regression model that we're going to
train in scikitlearn so if I move
something like here you can see that the
prediction changes from benign to
malignant for example there you go
um so I mean the objective of this I
mean the real world use case of an
application like this would be to plug
it to a cytology lab a cancer in a
Cancer Research Institute where you can
take some tissue from a breast and then
take some measurements from it login I
mean input the measurements here like
either automatically from the machine or
by hand visualize this measurements to
have an idea of what the cell cluster
looks like and then make a prediction
based on these measurements to see
whether the cell cluster is malignant or
not
um and yeah I mean it's pretty cool uses
data visualization machine learning
and and a web application that you can
deploy yeah by the end of the video
we're also going to deploy it so there
you go I am assuming that you know a
little bit about how machine learning
works and a little bit of familiarity
with the logistic regression model I am
also assuming that you have the basics
of python and I am going to use very
very little CSS and it is not essential
um so don't worry if you don't have a
CSS background
um and yeah so make sure to stick to the
end of the video to so that you have
this awesome
um project in your portfolio all right
there we go
all right so the first thing that we're
going to do
um in order to build this application is
to to train the model okay but before we
do that actually I just wanted to
mention that if you want a written
version of what we are doing right here
all with the Snippets of code that I'm
going to be using and the written
explanation of everything it is in my
you can find it in my blog everything
that you that you will find in this
video is also written in this blog post
I mean including the the code Snippets
and also be sure to check it out if you
want
um all right so back to this data set
um of course we need a data set to train
our model in order to be able to make a
prediction okay as you can see we are
trying to predict whether I'm cell
cluster is benign or malicious given
certain measurements that we're going to
take from it and that is exactly what we
have in this data set right here from
the University of Wisconsin it's a free
data set I will also put the link in the
description and the data set contains a
lot of variables of a lot of
measurements made to many different cell
clusters the measurements include for
example the radius mean of the cells the
texture mean perimeter mean Etc
and then it also contains a column with
the diagnosis of the cell cluster so if
it is M that means that the cell cluster
turned out to be a malicious cell
cluster and if it is B that means that
the cell cluster turned out to be a
benign so cluster this means that we can
train a machine learning model that is
going to take all of these variables as
predictors and it is going to predict
whether or not the the cell cluster is
benign or malignant
so in order to build this machine
learning model we're going to download
this data set
I have only it already downloaded it and
I included it right here in my project
but be sure to unzip the file and then I
just rename the file data.csv and then
put it right here
and then once that is done we are able
to start training our model
in order first in order to if you want
to better understand how machine
learning works and how especially
logistic regression works I invite you
to watch the video that I made about
that specifically because I use this
this same data set
in that video and
and I mean here we're just going to be
going through the cleaning and the model
building super fast I'm not going to be
explaining a lot of the logistic
regression part so be sure to check that
one if you if you have some
questions about that
um all right so now it's time to
actually start training our model the
data that we included right here
actually comes by itself already pretty
clean so we're not going to be doing
a lot of
exploratory data analysis either also
that's in the other video so I'm just
going to go through the cleaning super
quick so let's get right into that
all right so let's get right into it
um the first thing that we're going to
be doing is we're going to create our
project folder the project folder is
called streamlit app
um that cancer in my case but uh
extremely adapt cancer sorry and inside
of it we have a model folder and another
folder called date as I mentioned
already I already imported the data CSV
that I downloaded from kaggle right here
and this one right here is the model
this is the file where we're going to
train the model and this is also the
place where we're going to to clean the
data and to test that the model is
working correctly before exporting it
once we export it we're going to be able
to create a new folder right here which
is going to be the app folder and this
in it is in that folder where we're
going to be creating our streamlit
application but for now we'll have to
first create a model that we're going to
feed to our streamlit application
so that's what we're going to do in this
file right here
um right here as you can see I have this
basic condition
what this does is it tests that this
file is I mean it only executes what's
inside of it if the file is being
executed directly and not being imported
this is basically just
um standard convention convention thing
to do in order to make your code a
little bit more robust that way you can
be sure that the main content of your
application is not being run
accidentally when you import the file
somewhere else and it's only executed
when you actually want to execute this
file
so there you go and now let's just start
adding our data cleaning right here and
our model building and all so there we
go
all right so let's get right into it the
first thing that we're going to do is to
import pandas SPD that's basic in case
you don't have pandas installed you're
going to want to pip install
pandas in your terminal and once that's
done you should be able to use it like
this
now let's just import
actually what I'm going to do is I'm
going to create a new function right
here that is going to be called get
clean data
and then I'm just going to Define it
right here
Define
get clean
data there you go and this one first is
going to read the data file that we have
right here so we're going to do my data
is going to be equal to
PD dot read CSV
and we're going to read inside of data
and we're going to read data.csv there
is something strange going here I mean
like I'm not like super
I don't have a lot like super long
experience in Python so I I mean like
my intuition would be to actually go up
the model like the model folder and into
Data but actually it seems to I mean in
Python you just have to run it from the
root folder where the where you're
running the application so I mean all
right let's do it like that and then
we're going to be doing
we're going to be printing the head of
the data right so it's a data.head
to visualize it and we're just going to
return the data to see how it works so
there we go now if we click on enter on
read we should have our head right here
and now it's actually time to clean it
and to clean the data I mean you can do
it by hand like actually do an
exploratory analysis on the data and
that is what you should do if this is a
new data set but that I have already
worked with this data set and I know how
it looks like so I'm just going to clean
it super fast so that we go so that we
can go faster into building the
application okay so for example I know
that in my data
I have this column right here called
unnamed 32. and I know that I'm going to
want to drop it because I know that it
is all completely in the ends okay
so let's first do that
I'm going to the data dot drop
and oops
updated the drop and I'm going to drop
this one right here which is called
unnamed 32 like that and then I'm going
to say that it has to be dropped from
axis 1.
and then I am also going to drop the ID
column which I don't need either and
but um
I'm actually going to drop it from here
ID like that there you go and now the
diagnosis variable we have it that it
uses amps and B's and we're going to
encode it so that malicious I mean like
ends become zero and benign becomes uh
one now benign becomes zero and
malicious becomes one because we want to
test four malicious one
Malaysian cells so let's do that
so in order to do that we're going to be
using the map function and we're going
to be targeting the diagnosis
um the diagnosis column right here
and this one is going to be
diagnosis
diagnosis dot map and the map takes a
dictionary and in this dictionary I mean
of course it takes key value Pairs and
in the key you have the actual value
that you have currently and in the pair
you want to have the value that you want
it replaced with so malicious is going
to be one and benign is going to be
zero there you go now we can print now
we can
um I suppose that is the clean data
let's just check that out right here
print
um data dot head
there we go we save it we run it and now
we have the data that is being run and I
mean the head of the data we have the
diagnosis a lot of diagnosis of one and
we have the factor I mean like
I mean we don't seem to have the unnamed
column I'm just going to check it real
quick using the info
right here so as you can see we don't
have an unnamed column and we don't have
um we don't have the ID column anymore
and the diagnosis column is now once and
zeros so this is exactly what we wanted
so now as you can see we already have
the clean data and now we can actually
train our model from this data
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
do
um
create model
there you go and I'm going to Define
create
model
up here so let's do that right now
all right there we go so in order to
actually create our model we're going to
first have to pass in the data right
here that's something that I forgot the
data that we just got from our clean
data function right here we're going to
pass it right here
and inside of this function what we're
going to do first is we're going to
divide the data into
into the predictors and the target
variable okay so my predictors is going
are going to be called X
and I'm going to say data dot drop
and I'm just going to drop my diagnosis
right here I'm going to do axis 1 to be
sure that it's dropping the right part
um
there you go like that
and for y this one is basically just a
diagnosis column
there you go
um and now what we're going to want to
do is we're going to scale the data
first because as you can see on this
information from the data that we have
some variables are much larger than the
others like for example this one's in
the thousands and this one is just
decimals this one's in the hundreds so
in order for our model to actually
have uniform data it all has to be on
the same scale so that's what we're
going to do now and in order to do that
we're going to have to import the
the standard scalar from scikit-learn
okay so I'm going to do from sklearn
dot pre-processing I'm going to import
standard
scalar there you go and now I'm going to
be able to use it right here
so I'm going to say that my scalar is
going to be equal to standard scalar
like that and then we're going to
basically just scale all of my training
predictors okay because of course the
diagnosis prediction the diagnosis
doesn't need to be scaled because it's
already either zeros or ones okay
so my X is going to be
my X is going to be equal to scalar and
the Scala that I just created I'm going
to say fit transform
X to scale my X predictors there you go
so now we should have our our scaled
um
and we should have our scaled scalar
there you go and our scale data and now
what we're going to want to do is we're
going to split the data into testing and
training set okay here scale the data
I'm just going to comment it real quick
and then we're going to split
split the data super quick there we go
and and there we go now in order to
split it we're going to be using another
Library it's going to come also from
scikitlearn but this library is called
train test split I suppose you already
know it but I'm going to import it like
this right here model selection import
train
oops import train test split there you
go and now we can actually test and
import split our data into training and
testing set so my X train my X test
and then we have my y train then we have
my y test
there you go like that and this is going
to be equal to my train test split
and this one is going to take first it's
going to take my my predictors then my
my target variable
then I'm going to say that the test size
is going to be 20 percent
and I'm going to set a random state of
42 because that's the best number
and now that our data is split we can
actually train it now as you can now as
you can see we already have this train
which is 80 of our training predictors
and this test which is 20 of our
predictors
and same with the diagnosis the target
variable okay
so now for the train model we're going
to do auto equals logistic regression
but we have to first import logistic
regression from Psychic learn as well
and from sklearn dot linear model we're
going to
import
logistic regression like that then we're
going to use it right here there you go
and this is the model that we're going
to export to use it in the streamlit
application later okay so we're in order
to be able to actually use it we're
going to have to fit it to our data so
we have xtrain and Y train there you go
I'm going a little bit fast with this
training model part because I mean I'm
assuming that you already have a little
bit of knowledge on that but if you
don't all remember to check the other
video where I explain the logistic
regression
model and how it what is the intuition
behind it okay I go through this but in
much more detail
um so there we go and then finally once
we have it tested what we have it
trained we're just going to return it
and we're going to return the model and
we're also very important we're going to
return the scalar right here this is
going to be super important later
because we're going to be using it to
make our predictions later okay so here
that basically means that I'm exporting
the model and also the scalar
there you go
now that we have the model and the
scalar we can actually test the the data
so let's see we're going to test
our model
and that also means that I'm going to
have to create a new function right here
for testing okay
test D model
so Define
test model we're going to test the model
there you go
um all right so first of all wait just
let me be sure that this is actually
that this is actually working
does it run
seems to be running correctly okay we're
going to be testing it in a moment
anyways so there we go
ahead there we go so now it is time to
actually test the model to make sure
that it's working correctly
and to do that as I mentioned before we
have this test model function that we
are creating right here
and let's just create the test in order
to actually run the tests we're going to
be using also another library from
scikit-learn
I just wanted to mention that of course
here we're using scikit-learn to build
our machine learning model because we're
making a very simple prediction based of
a very simple
list of variables but this actually
works pretty much with any R2 which any
AI model all right so whether it be
machine learning or deep learning I mean
you can be running tensorflow here and
then build an application that makes
prediction it's based on tensorflow so I
mean the fact that I'm doing it with
psychic learn doesn't mean that you
cannot plug in a neural network right
here and make your predictions with that
okay just so as long as you're able to
export your model later as you will see
in a moment it should be okay
so we're going to test the model right
now
to test the model we're going to be
using first we're going to be using the
predict function from the model that we
just created and that we're importing
right here so let's do that we're going
to say that the Y predictions
um actually you know what we're just
going to test the model inside of here
so that we can actually have access to
all of this
there we go
um
we're going to test the model right here
train
the model
then we're going to test the model
and in order to test the model we're
going to create the predictions
protect
um yeah the Y predictions and they are
going to be based on the model right
here and we're going to run predict
and we're basically going to predict
under X test set okay as you remember we
trained it on the training part of the
predictors and now we're going to test
it on the on the testing part of the
predictors
um and then finally we're going to print
the accuracy
accuracy of our
model
and we're going to say that the accuracy
is the accuracy score
but in order to use the accuracy score
we're going to need to import that
function from scikit-learn
so from
scikit-learn dot metrics
we're going to import
accuracy score basically tells you how
how often you will write in your
predictions and also we're going to
import the classification report
there you go so for the accuracy of our
model we're going to say that we're
going to check the accuracy score and
this function takes two
two parameters the first one is the
actual values and the second one is your
predicted values for y okay remember
that the actual values are stored right
here in the test variable and the
predicted variables are the ones that
we're predicting with our model
and this should print out the accuracy
of our model and second of all
we're also going to print our
classification report
which is a more
a more in-depth
um analysis I mean in-depth report of
our model
so we're going to use the classification
report
and just as the previous one it takes
the the actual values for the
the actual values for diagnosis and then
our predictions
there you go
there we go and then just as before
we're going to be returning our model
and our scalar
there you go
now we should be able to run this and
let's see what it returns
okay so we have an accuracy of our model
of 97 which looks pretty good and here
is the classification report we have a
Precision of 97 for negative I mean for
benign
um
for benign cell clusters and a Precision
of 98 for malicious
um
for malicious cell clusters we also have
the other measures other statistical
measures right here like the F1 score
which is very important if our data set
is very
[Music]
if the yeah if the portion of actual of
actual positive diagnosis is very very
little
so there we go I mean our model seems to
be looking very good now it is now it is
time to actually export that model and
the scalar of course very important
and to start using it in our application
there we go
all right there we go now that our model
is script is pretty much ready
it should look something like this just
minimize the function so that it's
easier to for you to see what is going
on but as you can see we first created
the clean data function that I just
built super quick uh because I already
know the data but remember to perform
some some exploratory data analysis to
make sure that your data is
is clean before actually using it
and then we created the model also I did
that super quick because I already have
already worked with this data set but
also
um this should be like a a little bit of
a longer process uh if this is a new
data set for you
um and then we exported the scalar and
the model in order to be able to make
our predictions in our application okay
and now what we're going to do is we're
going to export the model and the scalar
in order to be able to use them inside
of our application this is very
important because you I mean sometimes
you might be tempted to just run this
code inside of your application that
would mean that it would be training a
machine learning model inside your
application every time someone
opens the app which is terrible for all
for usability I mean it's just going to
make your application way slower because
every time it's going to be opened it's
going to be training an entire machine
learning model I mean this one is a
little bit is quite fast because it's
just a logistic regression model on a
few
on very little data
uh but like anyways you should uh it
should be like uh something like you do
systematically that you build your model
uh apart and then you export it to a
binary file and then you import that
binary file into your application okay
and that is exactly what we're going to
be doing right now in order to do that
you're going to want to install first
um this package got called pickle pickle
five so in order to do that basically
you just do pip install pickle five it's
the one that we're going to use for
exporting our binary file then you're
going to import it like this import
pickle 5 as pickle and then we're going
to write a binary file with this
with this module okay so first we're
going to open
a new file we're going to call it model
dot pickle
and then the second argument of the
model we're going to say that we're
going to be writing in the in the file
and then it's a binary file that's what
the b stands for and we're going to say
sf4 file
and with this file we're going to pickle
oops
typical dot dump
and we're going to dump our model inside
the file there you go
um and then second we're going to do the
same thing with a scalar oops
scaler
dot pickle like this and just as before
we're going to say that we're going to
be writing on it and it's going to be in
binary mode as file there you go and
also we're going to pickle dump but this
time we're going to pickle dump our
scalar
and all we're going to dump it into our
file right here so there you go
um quite I mean like just as I mentioned
before even though we're running oh I
mean this file is being executed inside
of model we want to save it inside of
model itself so we do model
model like that that way the file is
going to be I mean the binary for
for our model is going to be stored
inside the model folder and same for
model for the pickle
folder right so there you go
um
so there we go now if we run this and we
save this we should
be able to see that our model that
pickle is being saved right here but our
scalar doesn't seem to be saved so no
such file or directory
assess it
right open pickle scalar f
um
[Music]
maybe I have to change this here
let's see if that works
not switch file or directory modal
scaler.pickle
all right yeah sure I added just like an
extra parenthesis right here
uh so yeah the G was not a problem
there you go now if we save it we should
have our model.pickle and ourscaler Dot
pickle like that there you go and these
are the files that we're going to be
importing into our application
so now that our model is built and our
scalar is built and both of these
binaries are exported it is time to
actually start building our streamlit
application with this okay so there we
go let's try get right into it
all right so now it's time to actually
create this app in order to do that as I
mentioned before we're going to create a
folder called app and inside of it I'm
just going to create another file called
main.py
there you go and it is in this file that
we're going to be running the
application
so just as before we're going to be
testing that the fat that this is the
file that is being executed and not that
it's being
imported somewhere else it's just like a
safety mechanism
then we're going to run main like this
there you go and now we're gonna have to
Define our main function
Main and we're going to say print
hello world
we will build streamlit
streamlit app
there we go
so now let's see how that looks Hello
World we will build a streamlit
application there we go
um so let's do this first of all what
we're going to want to do is we're going
to want to import
streamlit okay and in order to do that
you're going to have to have streamlit
installed streamlit is a python a python
library that allows you to
to
that allows you to oops nope
stream lit
ah
extremely to say python library that
allows you to build web applications
super quick
um basically around your around uh
around some data it's super useful to
create like dashboards or data
visualization applications or in this
case machine learning prediction
applications okay
and it's super fast you will see how how
we're going to
we're going to start up this application
with very little and very few lines of
code
so as I mentioned before you're going to
have to install it so you're going to do
pip install
it first
um I already have it installed so that's
going to be super fast
but then once you have done that you're
gonna have to come right here and do
import
streamlit as St
um
what is going on here that's SD there
you go then we're going to do import
pickle
pickle 5 as
pickle like that in order to actually
import our model and scaler
and we're going to import pandas SPD as
well in case we need it
so there we go so in our main in our
main function the first thing that we
are going to do is we're going to set
the page configuration for our
flower or
flower application so that goes St
page config
and here we're going to say that first
we need the page title page title
you know what I'm going to do it like
this page title it's going to be
breast cancer
predictor
there you go the second argument that it
takes is the page icon I'm just going
I'm not sure what I think it takes
seconds like this so I'm going to say
female
female doctor
supposed to work and the layout I'm
going to say it's white because I mean
if I just run it like this let me just
show you in order to write anything
where I'm just going to say right and
let's be
let's just do hello world
there you go if we save this file like
this and we do and we try to run it also
watch out in order to run this file you
cannot just do python
python your your app Main
.py because this is not going to
actually execute the application in
order to run the application you're
going to have to do streamlit run and
then actually Target the file that you
want to run that has the streamlined
application and then it's going to start
up oh it's going to start up this
um this app in your browser and as you
can see we have our app and it says
hello world which is the the text that
we wrote right here okay so just with
that we already have an application that
is up and running
so that's pretty convenient
and
now as you can see we have a a contained
layout it has a container right here
with a very big
like margin but we want it to be like a
wide layout so I'm just going to set
right here that this is going to be
layout
and delay is going to be white there you
go
and
and we are going to have a sidebar so
I'm going to say that the initial
sidebar state is going to be expanded
this one takes
expand it there you go
now if I save it and I rerun the
application
[Music]
rerun the application you can see that
the layout is white and I still don't
have a sidebar because I haven't created
it yet but as soon as I add a sidebar
it's going to appear open right here so
let's get on to that
[Music]
um so there we go that is the pretty
much the start for the streamlit
application the next thing that we're
going to do right now is we're going to
create the layout of our app create the
sidebar
some columns and then start populating
the columns okay so let's get right into
it
there we go so now what we're going to
want to do is we're going to want to set
a title for our app and set the set and
just write some explanation of it and
then just set the layout okay
now I come from web development so it
kind of is
a reflex to me to put everything inside
containers
and streamlate comes with containers
that actually just become divs in in the
H in the HTML code okay so in order to
create a container that is going to
contain some of some other elements you
do St container like that
and you're going I mean in order to
write inside of it you can do with
um the default python thing
and then in whatever you write inside of
here is going to be contained inside
this container right here
um and it's just a very convenient way
to structure your application
so right here we're going to do we're
going to write St title which basically
creates a H1 header and we're going to
call it rest
cancer
predictor
there you go
and then we're going to St right which
basically creates a p element which is a
paragraph in the HTML
and I'm just going to copy this
description right here from this file
that I have on the side in order to not
have to type it all
it's just a description of the
application for the users and to make it
easier for them to understand what is
going on
and now that I have this container right
here the container includes the
the title and the P element so let's
just start the application again and
there you have it you have our title and
then you have this quick explanation of
the application
uh the explanation rates please connect
this app to the cytology lab to help
diagnose breast cancer from your tissue
sample this app predicts using machine
learning model
what whether a breast mass is benign or
malignant based on the measurements it
receives from the cytosis laboratory
you can also update the measurements by
hand as you will as you remember we have
this we have this sliders that you can
update by hand but like ideally for an
application like this you would like you
would want to plug it directly into the
machine that is doing the measurement so
that you have the
the predictions immediately all right so
there you go
um now that this looks correctly we can
continue with
um with the layout that was one
container now we're going to create two
columns okay in the First Column is
going to be
is going to be this chart right here and
in the second column is going to be this
prediction
um box right here so let's do that in
order to create columns in streamlit you
can do St
dot columns
um this is important because
um just very a few months ago or years I
don't know
um this was a beta function so you had
to do beta dot columns Etc but now that
it's in the standard version you can
just do St columns and it works and this
one takes
um
okay I mean takes a list of how many
columns you want and the ratio of them
so I'm going to do four and one which
means that the First Column is going to
be
[Music]
um
four times as big as the as the as the
second one
and since we're creating two columns
this function returns two columns like
this call one and call two equals SD
columns four and one
and then just as we did with the
container we can write inside of these
columns by using the width
the width function from python so we do
St
sorry with column one
we're going to do St that right
this is column one
and then with oops with call 2 we're
going to do
St right which remember creates a p
element like a paragraph
and this is column two remember that the
first one is supposed to be four times
as big as the second one so let's see
how it looks
um am I running it or not
uh there you go so here this is column
one and this is column two as you can
see it's
um shorter than the column one by a
ratio of one to four
so there you go that seems to be working
correctly now what we're going to do is
we're going to
we're going to start
um with the sidebar we're going to
create our sidebar right here with all
of our inputs and then from those inputs
we're going to generate the chart and
the prediction so there we go
all right so what we're going to be
doing right now is to create our sidebar
for our application okay the sidebar
should look something like this
and it has as you can see right here it
has a slider for every single variable
in our data okay
so here we have our data and as you can
see we have around 30 predictors now if
I remember we dropped two columns
so we have 30 predictors
and so we should have around I we should
have 30 sliders one for its predictor
and depending on the value here we will
make our prediction and we will update
our chart right here all right
so in order to do this the first thing
that you want to do is to subscribe to
the channel and to like the video
because if you have come this far that
probably means that you're enjoying it
and it would be very good for me thank
you
um all right so now what we're going to
do is we're going to create this thing
right here
I'm just going to add it before the
container
um I'm going to make my own function and
where I'm going to actually create the
sidebar I'm going to show you a little
bit later why I'm doing this
um but let's see the first the first the
function is going to be called add
sidebar like this
and then I'm just going to create my
function up here add sidebar
fine add sidebarm
there you go
and now inside of here in order to
create a sidebar all you have to do is
do St sidebar and then just create a
heading for the sidebar I'm going to say
header sorry
I'm going to say that my header is going
to be called cell
nuclei measurements
there you go now if I save it and I come
back to the app that we are developing
now refresh here you have your sidebar
um there you go
so I mean just a quick note I don't
remember if I mentioned this already but
I mean in this example ideally you would
want this data to come directly from the
cytosis lab and to not have to update
all of them by hand
um but it's just that example right so I
mean ideally you would have this plugged
into a laboratory and then the
laboratory would fill the input values
automatically based on the measurements
from the machine and then like the the
researcher would be able to just tweak
some values to make sure that it's what
they intend
um so there you go so now we're going to
create this slot and this slide is right
here
but here we're
heading to a problem and it's the fact
that
as you can see inside of our app file we
don't actually have access to the column
names
or to the maximum values of the column
names because as you can see each site
each slider needs a maximum value so
that we know kind of like where to stop
this and to like in order to not set a
maximum value of 100 right here if all
the if all the values will be between 1
and 10 right that would be extremely
complicated to choose a value if all the
all the real values are actually just
like on this portion of the slider
so what we're going to do
there are two things that we could do
here
the more formal and correct way of doing
this is to export an object just like we
did with the model and the scalar from
the
when we're training our model export an
object with the information that we need
which would be the maximum value for
each column
and the column labels and the column
names for example
um since we are doing this like super
quick and this is and also since the
data is very very very small
like our data set is just a few hundred
a few hundred lines long so that means
that we can probably get away with
actually importing the data inside of
the app this is not what you would do in
a real production application
but we're just going to do it right here
to show you how how it would work like
just keep in mind that in a real world
scenario you would do this in the main
file and then just export it just as
with it with the pickle function
and import it right here
all right so let's do that
um I'm just going to create a function
where we get the data I'm actually just
going to copy it from here get clean
data
because remember that remember that we
want it clean
and now that we have the function of get
clean data
we are going to call it right here
inside the sidebar I'm going to say data
equals get clean data there you go
and now what we want is the column names
of the sidebar
inside of um finder inside of a list
right because we're going to want to
we're working on and also we're going to
need the labels of each of these sliders
right now I'm going to cheat a little
bit right here because I had this ready
I asked chai GPT to make it for me so I
mean that just makes it a little bit
easier because otherwise I would have to
to type all of this by hand
but the idea here is that you have a
list
with the label right here and the name
of the column right here so this is the
value that we're going to be using
um
as a label for our slider right here
and oops
um and here's the column name that we're
going to be using to actually access the
maximum value of that column okay
so I mean this is the same for for every
single column in our data set I mean you
would probably won't find a better way
of doing this but since charging PT just
does it super fast I just um asked it to
do it
and then once we have that information
what we're going to do is we're going to
Loop through all of these labels and all
of these column names and to create one
slider with each of them right
um so in order to do that we're going to
say that for
the label
and the key which are the two values
two values in my in my list
in this in this list we are going to
create St
ABA dot slider I'm just calling sidebar
because we want the slider to be inside
the sidebar but we could very well just
do SD that slider okay this is just to
put the slider inside the sidebar
and the slider we're going to say oops
we're going to say that for each element
in this list
the slider is going to take the I mean
the first argument that the slider takes
is the label
and we're just going to set it to the
label which is this one
um I mean the first value in our in our
value pairs
and actually I'm just going to
erase it like that I'm just going to say
label like that it's pretty much the
same thing and then for the minimum
value we're going to set it to zero
and then for the maximum value
um let's set it to 100 just just for now
just to show you what is happening
I'm going to save it
and right here let's just refresh
and there you go
you have
around I think it's 30 30 sliders that
go from 0 to 100 and each one of them
has the label
that we require so that's looking pretty
good so far
um now actually tweak it let's just
tweak it a little bit so that it
actually is what we intend it to be now
in here instead of it being a hundred
we're going to make it take the the
maximum value
in the column that we're in so in order
to do that we're going to take the data
that we previously imported which is
basically just the data set
and we're going to say that we're going
to pass in the key this is going to
select the column in the data Associated
to
to the variable that we're using so here
in this case for radius mean it's going
to take the column named radius mean
which is the column that contains the
data about the radius mean there you go
all right
so and this one we're going to take this
to take the maximum value right here
there you go
and in order to make sure that
everything's working correctly we're
going to convert it to a float
and if we save it right here this is not
going to work because this number right
here is an integer and it should be a
float as well in order for us to work if
I refresh this we have the problem that
it has the minimum value has an integer
type and the maximum value has a flow
type so in order to fix that we just do
float
there you go
then we refresh this and there you have
it now the maximum value is as it's like
something that makes more sense for for
this given for this given value so in
this case as you can see the area can go
to 200 2000 like 2500
and this one right here and the maximum
goes to just 0.16
so I mean that makes it way easier to to
actually visualize and to choose the the
real value for it
and now let's just set
um an average I mean like um
like a default value and we're going to
set pretty much the same here as heat
the same thing as we did here
but we're going to say that instead of
the maximum we're going to say that
we're going to take the mean value of
that of that column okay if we've got a
comma here
and then if I refresh
I should have the average value for each
one of them
it's looking pretty good huh
there you go
um and now
one thing that you may want to consider
is that this this right here actually
this function I mean the function slider
can Returns the value of the slider
so we're going to want to save that
somewhere in order to take that
information and build our chart and our
prediction right
just as a side note here we're using
sliders but remember that you can use
pretty much any HTML input element so if
I go to streamlit inputs
extremely inputs
here we have the input widgets that you
can use here like a checkbox a radio
button select box here we're using the
slider as you can see sd.slider
but like you can choose among any of
these and use them to build your
application right
so there we go now I was saying that
this function right here Returns the
value for each one of this
so what we're going to want to do is
we're going to create a dictionary
input
dictionary
and we're going to say that for each one
of this
we're going to create a new key value
pair in the dictionary that is going to
have as a key it's going to have the
column name
and as a value it's going to have the
current value of the of the slider so in
this case for example it's 14 13. that
means that in our dictionary the key
value pair with the key of radius mean
will have a value of 1413 and that is
the dictionary that we're going to use
to create the chart and the predictions
later on all right
so now we do that
and here what we're going to do is input
dictionary
and we're going to say that the here is
the key there you go
so this basically is doing what I told
you creating a key value pair well the
key is the name of the column and the
value is the value that the user input
in the slider and then we're just going
to return this dictionary
input dictionary like that
and then we can retrieve the data right
here input data will be equal to
whatever the sidebar returns and the
sidebar is returning the data from those
inputs
so now if we refresh this seems to be
working correctly and whenever I do this
it should be updating the value of my
input dictionary
so there you go now we have created our
let me just um let me see if I can show
you this
um Let's do an st dot write
um
can I write just input data I don't know
if I can do this let's see
yeah there you go so I mean like here
I'm just like this is just for tests
right
every time I update this you can see
that this one is being updated
this one is being updated I mean like
what I'm doing here is I'm just
outputting the data that comes from the
sidebar
so now this is
this is basically what we need what I
told you the key value Pairs and we're
going to be building our chart from this
and our prediction
um later on from this as well so there
we go I'm just going to remove that
there we go so let's get to building
these two parts
all right so now it is time to complete
our application with a charge right here
that is going to take the values from
our input elements that we have on the
sidebar okay
um we want a we'll want a chart to look
something like this
the chart is a radar chart that's how it
is called and it has different values
right here and the on the on the
circumference
and it has different values here on the
radiuses right radii yeah
um
and the idea is that you will have the
perimeter the texture and the radius and
you will have three values for each one
of this you have the mean the standard
error and the worst value uh for that
one in the cell cluster
um all right something to keep in mind
is that this are not the same column all
right so
um how to put this in simple terms
so the mean radius is one column the
standard error for the radius is another
column and the worst value for the
radius is another column all right so
it's not one single column from which
we're taking the mean the worst value
and the standard error they are
different
columns in our data set and that's
basically just how our data set arrived
so that's how we're working with it
um so as you can see here you can see it
clearly here you have the radius mean
you have the radius standard error and
then you have the radius
um worst value which should be here
there you go
um so basically what we're going to do
is we're going to create this chart and
we're going to map we're going to map
the values from the mean from the
standard error and from the worst part
of the data set into each part of these
traces okay so let's do that in order to
build this chart we're going to be using
a JavaScript library that has a python
module called plotly it's super powerful
and it's it makes interactive charts
unlike for example
Seaborn or Matlab here you have like an
interactive chart that you can play with
I'm not sure if this is working
um yeah here we have an interactive
chart that you can play with
um I don't know what this is what's
going on here
Zoom
um
yeah uh I don't know for some reason
there is a bug here in my JavaScript I
suppose
yeah but I mean the thing is that you
can you can usually play with it uh we
should be able to do that in a moment
but yeah I mean it's a very nice library
and it is the documentation is right
here okay
um what we're going to be doing is we're
going to be copying this example from
the documentation and we're going to be
upload upgrade and in updating it with
our own data okay so let's do that
I'm just going to copy this well first
of all I'm just going to add my function
right here instead instead of the text
this is column one we're going to write
um get Trader
chart and this is going to be a function
that takes as an argument my input data
that we are retrieving from the sidebar
do you remember that we're getting the
dictionary of values from the sidebar
and this is the dictionary of values
that we are
injecting into our I mean we're passing
to our data chart as an argument
so let's now create the function get
um
radar chart like this
and inside of it we're going to actually
just add the code
that comes in the example of our
documentation
something to keep in mind is that you're
going to have to install plotly first so
in order to do that it's very simple
you're just going to do
um pip install plotly I already have it
installed so I'm not going to do it but
once you do that you're gonna be able to
import plotly right here
like that
um using just as in the example from the
documentation graph objects which is a
part a module of the plotly library that
allows you that gives you a higher level
of customization in your charts but
something that you can do is also use
like
I mean if you're using plotly for other
things you can use the express module
which makes allows you to make charts
with predefined
characteristics
with way less code but since we want to
be since we want it a little bit more
customized we're going to go for this
one and we're going to just copy this
example right here
now that we have this right here
uh notice that here at the end they have
fake.show that basically just renders
the plotly chart in in the page but this
is not where we're going to be using
because
um streamlit uses its own function to
incorporate
um plotly yellow I mean plotly elements
into the application so what we're going
to do is instead of doing fict.show
we're just going to return
return the figure like that
and right here
we're going to
Raider we're going to get that figure
which this function is going to return
and we're going to use this streamlit
function called St dot plotly chart
there you go
and then we're just going to call in
we're just going to pass in the figure
element
that we got from from the function
so now if we save this we should have
this chart in our page let's see if we
refresh does it work
and there seems to be a problem here uh
Raider chart takes zero positional
arguments okay I forgot to add input
data here there you go now if I refresh
there you go now we have our
our rated chart uh it's looking pretty
good now what we want is to it to
actually take the real values that we
wanted to take
and in order to do that it's actually
very simple let me just show you what is
going on in the in the chart
so here as you can see we have five
different values that the traces can
take
mechanical properties processing codes
Etc right and this ones correspond to
the categories list right here and they
have they correspond to the
to the parameter Theta Theta Theta Theta
and this is basically just the
yeah yeah the the values among the the
yeah the angular the angular values all
right and the r or the radial value so I
mean the distance uh from the center to
the actual maximum value that each value
has right I hope it's clear there you go
so here for example we have categories
the first element in the categories list
is processing cost and here the first
element of this Trace which is product a
is one and here we have it that it is
the value for that one is one right here
and the processing cost is the value
Associated to it okay
same thing mechanical properties is the
second one and here it is number five
the value for that one so it Maps two
mechanical properties and here we have
it it was one for processing cost and it
is five for mechanical values okay so
all that we're going to want to do is
we're going to replace this with our own
values
that are here which come from radius
texture perimeter Etc
and we're going to replace the r values
with the values that come from our input
data that comes from our sidebar okay
very simple
it might get a little tricky and while
we're doing this but stay with me it's
not that hard just just feel free to
replay this um this part of the video If
at some point you get stuck or just ask
me in the comments if you have any
questions okay
all right so what we're going to do is
first of all we're going to replace the
values on the
on the perimeter with the actual values
that we want so
let's do that so we have processing cost
here and I have my list of values right
here where is it
here it is
and this is their list of values that
I'm going to be using
there you go
we go from radius to texture area and
cavity fractal Dimension Etc
there you go
and now these are the categories and we
have one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten values right here
that we have to assign in each one of
these traces okay
I forgot to mention the what this thing
these two things are this is basically
just the name of the trace here it is
product a and product B and in our
application they are going to be mean
standard error and worst okay
and the fail it just tells plotly that
it wants the
the figure to be filled with color okay
so if I set this one to none for example
we won't have a ready color here like a
red color here we'll just have like an
empty space with the line around it okay
um so there you go
um so let's just complete it here we
have the categories and now let's use
the data in our input data to complete
the values inside of the chart
and the right and the values come right
here and I'm going to say
nope it's not
there you go
there you go and right here I'm just
going to add the values I already have
them copied on the side but I'm just
going to start typing them here so that
you get an idea of what they refer to
and then I'm just going to copy them
from my code that I have on the side
um the idea right here is that you're
going to take the input data
and remember what is input data the
input data is the value that we're
getting inside the function
and the value that are we're getting
inside the function comes from the
sidebar and you remember what the
sidebar returns
decide by returns a dictionary a key
value pair
a dictionary of key value pairs remember
that in the key it has the name of the
column and in the value it has the value
of the sidebar
so what we want right here is to take
[Music]
um
is to take the key that that is
associated to the mean value here let's
just update this one mean
value the key that's associated to the
mean value of the radius okay so it is
the key
that's associated to this slider right
here this is the one that is going to be
mapped onto
the radius the radius part of the mean
Trace okay
stay with me there we go so here it's
going to be radius mean like that
the second one is going to be
input data and it's going to be texture
mean and what is the name the key of
this value well it's very easy it comes
from this array right here the first one
is radius mean the second one is text
Charming
so we're going to take that one we're
going to put it right here like that
there you go and like that we're going
to do like that for every single one of
our
input data
um that the for our input data that
comes from our sidebar that's about the
mean okay because remember that we have
the mean
we have the standard there and we have
the worst value so we're going to do
that for all of them up until here all
right
so I have that
right here
let me just copy it and paste it here
there you go so it's exactly what we
were doing before
this is a list
with all of our elements
there you go the first one is the radius
main texture mean Etc all the way to
fractal Dimension mean and this comes
from the object that we exported from
the sidebar all right
the Theta is the same categories and
there you go looking pretty good now
same thing for the second one the second
one is not going to be the mean value
it's going to be the standard error
and this one is going to take the values
of
this one radius standard error up until
this one right here okay and it's
basically just exactly the same thing as
the same thing as the previous one
we take
the R value
and we paste the input data like this
um here I'm just going to do like that
there you go
I'm going to
some spaces there you go oops
just make this a little bit more
beautiful and easier to read input data
symmetry standard there and I'm missing
fractal mean
yep I mean which is not a mean it's
actually the standard error so there you
go here we have standard error like that
and like that there you go so just as
before we have the input data for each
one of this
and here instead of targeting the first
the first 10 one we're going to Target
the second from from the second ten one
from the 11 to 20. that's that's which
are the variables Associated to the
standard error
and we're going to do the same thing for
the third Trace which is going to be the
worst value for each one of this
and here it's going to say worst
worst value this is the name of the
trace
and here instead of radius SE it's going
to be radius worst and the same for all
of them just going to copy them from the
side
mm-hmm
[Music]
like this
there you go so now we have
[Music]
um
radius worse texture worst all the way
to fractal Dimension worst and this are
going to map to our categories okay
so there we go
now if we save this we should have a
radar chart that looks a little bit
correct but it's not going to be correct
yet
um yeah the thing is that
um
[Music]
let's see if what if I do something like
this
there seems to be an error here
um
everything seems to be falling on 0.4
for some reason
um
r r r
categories to sell forced value
the range
return figure we're going to show
the legend
um what's going on here
what do we have here
we must have an error somewhere right
here
um maybe we're adding too many values
here fractal them from radius to fractal
Dimension one two three
ten
three though
that's ten all right what's going on
here
um maybe this shouldn't have space here
I don't think that's it let's see
no
all right give me a second
all right sorry about that the air was
this little thing right here okay so we
were defining our categories but we had
this coma right here so it didn't know
what this was but now that we remove it
and that we leave it like that it
actually sees that every single one of
this has a different
um it's a different element from the
list okay so there we go now our radar
chart is looking
pretty decent I mean not yet but it's
getting closer to that
so there we go we have different values
for fractal Dimension concavity Etc
um all right so now what we're going to
want to do is we're going to have to
scale all our values okay
and how do we scale them
um so the thing is that here you have
for example the perimeter can go from
zero
to 188
which is a ridiculous like a
ridiculously high value compared to for
example smoothness which can only go to
0.16
what we are going to do is we're going
to scale all of these values to get them
to get them between 0 and 1 that way we
can have a range for our
we can create a range for our for our
radar chart so that if it's zero it's
closer to here and if it's one it's
closer to here
um because I mean if we set it to a
thousand for example
let's set it to 2000 and 2500
if we refresh this I mean it's going to
be all right for them for the area value
which is in the thousands but it's going
to be too big for all of the others
right so
like if I put this one here I mean it
will be able to detect it but let's just
scale every single one of them between
zero and one okay so let's do that right
now in order to do that I'm just going
to set the range to zero to in between 0
and 1 I'm going to scale all of the
values so that they be between 0 and 1.
to do that let's create a new function
that is going to be
um
um get
scaled values I suppose you can also I
mean and this is going to take a
dictionary okay input dictionary
I suppose you can also use scikit-learn
for this I'm just going to do this by
hand because I don't know it was just a
little bit faster but I suppose you can
do it with scikit-learn as well
so what we're going to do to get the
scaled values
is we're going to we're going to get the
data first
um get clean data remember that is the
function that we created before and with
this data we're going to take also just
the predictors
so it's going we're going for to do that
we're going to drop the diagnosis part
um oops
data dot drop
[Music]
diagnosis and we're going to drop it on
axis
axis 1 like that if I'm not mistaken
and now we're going to create the scale
dictionary which is the one that we're
going to return okay
and what we're going to do is that for
we are taking the input dictionary right
so for the key
and the value pairs inside the
dictionary
uh
input dictionary and for the items so
that we are looping through the key
value pairs
what we're going to do is we're going to
say that the maximum value
is going to be equal to
X
and then the key for this element in the
value which I mean remember that we're
dealing with our
with the original dictionary of value
key value pairs that we were working
with before we're going to do Max
and then the same thing but for the
minimum one
the minimum value is going to be equal
to the minimum one and then the scaled
value
which is the one that is going to have
like all right so this is a little bit
more of mathematics but basically we are
taking the maximum value in the in the
given column and the minimum value in
the given column and then we're we're
getting the scaled value based of that
taking the value of the actual
um of the actual input
minus the minimum value
over the maximum value
um
minus the minimum value oops
uh
not mean value mean vowel like that
and this is basically just going to give
us a scaled value
um a value between between 0 and 1 for
every single value in our
in our input dictionary okay I suppose
you can also use
a scalar from scikit-learn but I don't
know I just found it faster to do it
this way so now in the scale dictionary
we're just going to replace the key
um in the value of the key which is this
one with our new scaled value
there you go and then let's just return
the scale dictionary like that okay I
hope I didn't lose you there basically
all that we're doing is taking I mean
this function basically just takes the
input dictionary with all the values
from this input right here
and it looks in the data for the maximum
and the minimum
possible value for this one and then it
just performs some operations I mean
this separation right here which will
always be between zero and one okay so
the low the closer it is to the minimum
value the closer it will be to zero and
the closer it is to the maximum value of
the same column the closer it will be to
one so it will the this function will
return
and in production a dictionary that
looks exactly as the one that it's
taking but with values between zero and
one okay and this is the one that we're
going to be using right here in our in
our radar chart
our input data
so the input data is going to be equal
to get Scaled values
of itself
and now
it should all of the data that came
right here will be treated as values
that are between zero and one so let's
see how this works
now if we refresh this oh and remember
that we have updated our range to be
between 0 and 1 because now all of our
values are going to be between 0 and 1
right
now if we refresh this there we have it
now all of your values
are going to be between
0 and 1. even if it's 2500 if I get it
to the maximum it's just going to be 1
and if I get it to the minimum it's just
going to be zero all right
so there you go
um now that we have scaled our values
and our rated chart is ready we are
ready to pass on to the prediction part
of the application so there we go good
job so good job to now
there we go all right so now it is time
to create this prediction part in our
application okay I I just wanted to
mention that congratulations for making
it up to here to here this is a quite a
long project so um and you have done a
lot a lot of work so far so great job
congratulations and let's just finish
this application so that we can deploy
it and show it in your portfolio all
right so
um what we're going to do now is we're
going to build these predictions right
here
and we're going to do that replacing
this function right here with a function
called
add predictions like that
there you go and then we're just going
to have to create the function up here
add predictions
and this function is going to take the
input data right
because we're going to make the
predictions using the input data from
the user and that input data comes from
here there you go
so now the first thing that you're going
to want to do is to
is to import the model and the scalar
that we exported before from when we
were creating the model okay do you
remember that we are not
training the model inside of the
application but we're just importing it
right so let's do that in order to do
that we're going to first import the
model from pickle remember that I had
already imported piccolob here
so we're going to do pickle
dot load oops pickle.load
and we're going to do open
and the location of our model which is
inside the model and model.pickle
model oops model and model Dot
pickle there you go
and then we're just going to say that
we're going to open it in read mode and
it's a binary file yeah R is for read
mode and R and B is for binary mode
there you go and let's do the same thing
for the scalar okay
the scalar is also inside model but it's
called scalar.pickle
there we go
um all right so now what we're going to
want to do is we're going to convert
this input data dictionary because
remember that this is this is a
dictionary with key value pairs in the
key is the name of the of the parameter
right so radius mean radius standard
error texture mean texture standard
error and the value is the actual value
that the user input here right so what
we're going to want to do is we're going
to convert that into a single array with
um
a single array with the values right
and in order to do that what we're going
to do is we're going to use numpy all
right so let's just import numpy
import numpy
SNP there you go and right here we're
going to say that the in oops input
array
and we're going to convert all the
values from our input data dictionary
into a numpy array okay so we're going
to say NP array
we're going to select it as a list
the input data
and we're going to select only the
values right
now if we save this
let's see let's do an st right
and just pass in this input array all
right so right now we should have
we should be showing the input array of
only the values
of this one right here in our prediction
side okay so let's see if that worked
let's refresh and there you hope there
you go you have this
um 30 29 values no 30 values
um and it's only it's just an array with
um with all of this with the values that
we input right so if we change this one
for example to 138 this one is going to
change there you go you can see that
it's reactive right and that is that is
exactly what we want because we want to
make the predictions uh when chain when
updating the inputs right so what we're
going to do though is to reshape it
because our model actually takes a two
dimensional
um array not a single Dimension array so
we're going to do reshape
one minus one like this then if we
refresh it there you go that's how it
that's how it that's how it's supposed
to look right it's supposed to have like
every single variable is supposed to be
one single column
um
uh yeah so there you go now what we're
going to want to do
is scale it because as you can see right
now the values are exactly what we set
them here to so for example this one is
14 13. and this one is 14. uh I mean 14
27 12 7 right
um and we want all of them to be scaled
with the same scalar that we use to
create our model because otherwise the
model is not going to work
so let's scale them with the model that
we just imported that is why it was so
important to you create and to export
the scalar with the model when when we
run on this spot
so let's scale it in order to scale it
I'm
I'm going to say
but
array
scaled
and I'm going to use my scalar that I
just imported like this scalar dot
transform
and I am going to say that I'm going to
transform this input array right here
and now if I write this one instead of
the other one you can see that
everything has a value of zero
and why is that good question
the thing is that
remember that we set the default value
of each one of our sliders to the mean
value of the entire column
we did that up here if I'm not mistaken
um sidebar there you go so we set the
value of each one I mean the default
value of each one of our of our sliders
to the mean value of the column so
in the scalar since this what the scalar
does is to take all of the values of the
column and if it's very high
make it closer to
to
to the mean and if it's very low bring
it closer to the mean and then put
everything in the same like in the same
scale right if that makes any sense
um so what's happening basically is that
since everything is in the mean
everything is at zero but when we move
something a little bit let me just move
the first one so that it's easier to see
I move it below the mean then it's going
to become negative and if I move it
above the mean then it's going to become
positive same with the second one Etc
right so if you only see zeros at the
beginning don't worry that's completely
normal and that's how it's supposed to
work all right
so there we go now that we have this
scaled values we can actually fit them
to our to our prediction model to our
model to make prediction sorry
so let's see now we can say that the
prediction
is going to be we're going to use our
model and we're going to say
predict
just as we did when we were testing the
model we're just going to say predict
and we're going to pass in the input
hmm
oops
input array scaled there you go and now
we can just export the prediction like
that
there you go now we can if we refresh it
you can see that the prediction is zero
which means that it is benign
but if we move something a little bit
too high then it's going to be 1 which
is malicious all right so that's
up to here we are already using machine
learning to make a prediction in the
model using our model and to show it in
the front now let's just make it a
little bit
um like user friendly
so instead of writing just a prediction
we're going to say that if
the prediction
so the prediction is an array so if the
prediction if the first and only element
of the prediction is zero
we're going to St right
and I have it right here
we're going to pop them right
we're going to say
benign
and else
we're going to say
malicious
there you go and now we don't need this
part right here
now if I refresh this
there you go benign
and then if I oh
then it is malicious there you go it's
looking pretty good and now let's just
add another part right here which is
going to be the probability of it being
benign or not right so we're going to do
as well St right
and we're going to say the probability
probability of being benign
is
and we're going to say that the model
and we're going to say predict
probe
probability and we're going to say the
input data
input array scaled
um
zero and zero because this one returns
all right so this one right one second
so this right here predict probability
returns an array with two with two
elements the first one is the
probability of it being
zero and the second one is the
probability of it being one if I'm not
mistaken
and then we're going to do exactly the
same for the second one but instead of
choosing the first element which is the
probability of it being benign or it
being zero we're going to take the
probability of it being 1 which is
malicious
there you go then we will save it
we should be able to see what's going on
here there you go so we have benign
probability of it being benign 0.50 I
mean 50 58 and probability of it being
malicious 41 it's looking pretty good
um and now what we're going to do I'm
just going to add another line right
here at the bottom just to mention like
um
clarification that this app is
only use only intended to assist
Professionals in making a diagnosis but
should not be a substitute for a
professional diagnosis so there you go
now if we save this we have we can
refresh it and there you go now you have
your application with this really nice
um
really nice
um column right here which tells you if
the
if the if these cells are benign or
malicious
so there you go I'm just going to add a
little sub header and header right here
just to make it a little bit more
um
user friendly so I'm going to say SD
subheader
and I'm going to say cell cluster
prediction
and then I'm going to St
right
the cell cluster oops cluster s
and then should there you go cell
cluster prediction the cell cluster is
B9 probability of being benign
probability of it being malicious and
then just our little text right here
there you go
um now
there you have it now I mean
your app could be finished right now I'm
just going to add a little bit of styles
right here but
um for what we have been doing so far
this should be
um like already you have a very good app
that is working
I'm just going in the next part of the
video I'm going to show you how to
update a little bit these styles with
some CSS
and yeah and then I suppose we can
deploy it so there we go
awesome so now just for the record our
application looks like this it looks
pretty complete and the code looks
something like this okay so we have our
main function where we set up the page
configuration using the streamlit
configuration
then we add the sidebar that Returns the
input data in a dictionary
then inside a container we added the
title and some description of the
application then we just added our two
columns one of which is
um four times as big as the second one
and then for the First Column we added a
radar chart with this function right
here
and we are displaying it using the
streamlit function plotly chart and not
just showing it right and then for the
second column we're adding the
predictions using the machine learning
model and the scalar that we had
previously created and that we exported
using pickle right now what we are going
to do is kind of an optional part of the
video
is to style it a little bit more with
CSS right I know that streamlit is not
thought of
in order to I mean it's not made to use
CSS on it but you can use okay it's
unlike Dash it's kind of a little bit
more complicated to do it but you can so
I'm just going to show you how to do it
but in general if you're using extremely
to try to try to stay close to the
default styles from from the framework
all right so what we're going to do is
we're going to create a new file in well
first we're going to create a new folder
called assets
and inside assets we're going to create
style that
a file called style.css
for my fellow well web developers this
is probably where things are starting to
get familiar
so in order to actually just make some
modifications and that's why why I meant
that this is probably not the weight
like
streamlit is not thought oops it's not
made to do this but you can see that we
have
I can just check right here inspect this
element and try to find where my box is
right here so it seems to be this one
and I can just copy the class
um chips
there you go I copy the class then I
then I use it to modify it right and
basically what I'm going to do with this
one is I'm just going to set a
padding of one REM as I mentioned this
is completely optional you don't
necessarily need to know CSS but I mean
it helps
I'm just going to set a simple border
radius oops
for the radius of
um half
an RM
and finally I am going to set a
background color to
to this color that I have right here
which blends very well with the
background
so let's see how that looks like so far
um well of course for now we're not
going to see anything because we haven't
imported it into our file okay and in
order to import it into the application
there's it's some sort of a hack
because it's not I mean as I mentioned
streamlit is not made for this
but we are going to just hack around it
a little bit to make it display our our
[Music]
to make it show our CSS okay and to do
that we're going to
add the CSS as though it was a markdown
file okay so right here under the page
configuration I'm going to say with open
and I'm going to open my file
which is
which is inside assets
style dot CSS
as
f for file
and I'm going to say that I'm going to
add some markdown
okay as I mentioned this is a hack it
basically just Imports the file into the
website and
and streamlit things that this is a
markdown file but it actually contains
CSS and it's going to modify
the style of the of the web application
but it's kind of not what it's intended
to
um with like this Magnum function right
and inside of here we're going to add
our style tags
like this
and inside the style text we're going to
add our file and I'm going to say format
we're going to say the F dot read to get
the contents of our file
and then we're just going to say that
unsafe
allow HTML to be able to parse it as
HTML okay
uh so there you go this should I think
make us
um format
yeah I mean this should import our
Styles file as a markdown file but not
really into our into our file and it
should update the style of this box
right here which has this class so let's
see if that worked
there you go so it worked oh we just
added a little bit of padding and just
changed a little bit some of these
things so to me that looks pretty
alright
um and the second thing that I'm going
to do just to make it a little bit more
um complete
I am going to I'm going to add a few
I'm going to make this one right here
turn to red when it's benign and
um sorry blue sorry green when it's
benign and red when it's malicious all
right so let's do that in order to do
that we're going to have to modify the
code that we added in the in the ad
predictions right here so as you
remember we added B9 and malicious
depending on the prediction but here
we're going to wrap it in a span element
which is a HTML element
and we're going to give it a class of
um
a class of
diagnosis
benign
and then we have we're of course going
to have to close the span there you go
and if we save this like this actually
and we refresh you can see that this
span is actually not being parsed as
part of the HTML in order to make the
HTML elements that we put in into these
strings to be passed we need to add this
other
[Music]
um parameter right here which says on on
safe allow HTML and set this one to true
this one is going to allow us to parse
the HTML inside of it and now if you see
benign is actually
um
inside a span with classes diagnosis and
benign so now we can Target those
classes in the CSS style sheet right and
we're going to do pretty much the same
thing for
for our malicious one so let's copy this
and let's paste it right here diagnosis
malicious
now let's just close this pen
there you go and now we can Target that
right here
so diagnosis
is going to have a
second it's going to have a color
oops
color of white
it's going to have a padding
of 0.2 grams and
0.5 you know what we're going to use EMS
here 0.5
Rems because we're dealing with uh with
a yeah with this kind of button I don't
remember how to call these things
and then we're going to say that the
Border radius is going to be 0.5 EMS
there you go
and now we're going to Target the
background depending on whether it has a
class of
of malicious or benign okay so let's say
the diagnosis dot benign
is going to have a background color
of this screen that I have right here I
just looked up some nice looking green
beforehand
and then the same thing but for
malicious okay
and for malicious I'm going to use this
red color right here
um one second this red color right here
I also checked it out before
there we go so malicious like that
benign like that and my classes they're
supposed to be malicious and benign
there you go so now if I refresh this
benign there it is we should have um you
know what let's yeah benign should have
um green background and malicious
um oh I forgot to add
unsafe allow HTML here unsafe
unsafe allowed HTML to true there you go
now if I refresh benign has a green
background and malicious
hum what's going on here hmm
apparently they're showing both
um
[Music]
what's going on here
why is why are both being shown
it's only supposed to show one of them
what's going on here let's see
refresh
benign and
huh
oh yeah sorry I guess I'm I'm blogging
malicious here and benign by the side so
malicious right here and then there you
go like that
now it's going to work now if we refresh
there you help there you go now you have
benign in green
and if you turn into malicious oh
foreign
sorry about that
um so now you have benign in green and
malicious in red and you have the
probabilities that are also being
updated
um reactively all right
um so there you go now the application
is pretty much complete I would say
um
and of course you can play around and
add some other CSS code but I wouldn't
recommend it I mean I just added some of
it right here to make it look a little
bit
um more user friendly and just like I
figure that the color is red and green
looked very good
there might be some options to do this
extremely by default but since I just it
was pretty easy to just do it with CSS
so there you go I mean I hope this um
now you have like your final application
congratulations Bravo Now
I hope this was cool for you now what
we're going to do is we're going to
deploy it so that you can share the link
to our future employer or with your
friends and to show them what you built
and to get a job that pays you hundreds
of thousands of dollars right
so there you go let's do that all right
awesome so the application is looking
very good uh now we have this app that's
looking like it works it works it looks
perfectly and all now you're going to
want to up and deploy it and in order to
share a link and then your employer can
visit it and your friends can visit it
and you can just show off and feel very
good about it okay
um the idea is that we're going to be
using a resource from like a service
from streamlit called Community Cloud
okay there are different ways to deploy
to to this to deploy streamlined
application as you can see it's just a
regular application
and you can deploy it in a like if you
go to the documentation you can see that
they offer
um tutorials on how to deploy it on with
Docker kubernetes and to to any to any
hosting that you want but here we're
going to be using streamlined Community
Cloud it's the fastest and easiest way
to do it and it's free so why not
so what we're going to do is we're going
to go to streamly.io slash cloud sorry
like that
and then we're going to sign sign up if
you don't have an account of course
and once you have signed up you're going
to be able to sign in and to see a
dashboard that looks like this one okay
um this was just some tests that I had
that I had started a moment ago just
delete this
up um oops not like that
it's going to delete this
there you go all right so your app your
dashboard is going to look something
like that okay what you're going to do
right now
is uh first of all you're going to have
to connect your GitHub account okay
and once you have connected your GitHub
account you're going to want to create a
new repository in this case I created a
repository called streamlit cancer
predict
and once you have created that
repository that is what you're going to
be using to deploy to to streamlit Cloud
okay
so once you have done that we're going
to come right here to our to our
application and we're going to say get
init if you haven't if you haven't been
tracking your code which is a very bad
practice by the way sorry about that
sorry about that
um and then just add everything right
it's going to add everything and get
commit oops
git command and we're going to say
first
commit and
first commit and finish app terrible way
to make a commit but there you go
um so now we have our app that is
already tracked and get it has been it's
now it's like the repository is complete
now we have to upload it here what we're
going to do is we're going to copy this
one right here I'm going to add it
to my git remote
at origin if I'm not mistaken to add an
origin for this one I'm just going to
paste the URL and now you find that
mistaken
I should have it right here there you go
now what I want to do is I'm going to
push it to my remote repository in
GitHub right what we're doing here is
basically just push everything right
here to GitHub
so we're going to do git push U origin
Main
and now if we refresh this our GitHub
should have the all our files good
so there we go now what we're gonna have
to do before actually deploying to
streamlit is we're going to have to tell
our application what are the modules and
the packages that we're using right
because
remember that during our
while developing our application we used
several several several packages so we
used pickle we used pandas which plus
plotly we use numpy and what streamlit
cloud does is it creates a virtualized
server and once it's virtualized it
doesn't necessarily have all these
packages installed so we're going to
have to tell it which packages you're
going to need if you come from from
JavaScript this is exactly the same as
creating an npm
package.json right
so in order to create our package.json
or our list of dependencies we're going
to do we're going to need a new
dependency from python called pip Rec
okay so in order to do that we're going
to have to install it first we're going
to do pip install
pip wreck if I'm not mistaken
there you go and then in the origin of
our file we're just going to do pip
wreck
and then usually you would you would
write where you want your file to be but
here I'm just going to say pip rack and
it didn't work
um pip wreck is probably
[Music]
wreck
let's see does that work what's going on
um
one second
[Music]
um
let's see
what you're going to want to do oh sorry
it's not peep wreck it's people Rex yeah
sorry about that it's paper x with an S
so there you go now I have to install
this one and then I do pip Rex with an s
there you go and now you have your
requirements.txt right here there you go
now as you can see this is a file that
basically includes all of your
dependencies I mean the packages that
you installed so that streamlit cloud
can install them
um in in their own server and so that
your application is able to run okay so
now that we have this we're going to
have to get at our requirements
requirements.txt
[Music]
all right so I already added it so
that's right and then we're going to
have to commit it
add requirements and that git push
to our
origin Main and now we should have our
requirements
right here there you go so that should
be enough to tell our streamlit Cloud
application service that we want to
deploy using these requirements so now
we go to our dashboard
that's here we click on new app Remember
to link your GitHub account
and then you're going to say which is
the repository that you're going to want
to deploy it from which is the one that
we just created streamlit cancer predict
the branch is the main branch that we're
using and the file the path to the file
okay here it already detected that it's
inside app and Main which is app and
Main which is this file that we're going
to want to to execute to load our
application
and now we can click on let's see do we
have advanced settings I mean you can
set up Secrets if you need to but I
didn't add any so we can just deploy
and it sometimes takes a little while
because it needs to it needs to
install all the dependencies and just to
get your app up and running
but it usually works very well and now
as you can see we have deployed our
application super quick
um hopefully there will be no errors so
if you got all the way to here thank you
very much and congratulations you have
um completed a a very very long course
and you know now how to create
streamlined applications that make
um predictions with a machine learning
model and you learned how to export that
model that you created in Python and how
to export it with pickle how to import
it your application and how to use that
to take some input from your user and to
make predictions based on that input and
we also learned how to make a really
like a pretty sophisticated chart
from the input that the user gives and
to update the chart reactively
so I would say that you have done an
amazing job so congratulations and now
here you go now your application is up
and running and it's in the and it's in
the web
so you can just copy this URL and share
it with your friends with your with your
employers and to show how amazing your
skills are at at machine learning and at
creating web applications using machine
learning Technologies okay as a reminder
that you can use pretty much any machine
learning
um I mean any model it doesn't have to
be like a logistic regression which is
super simple you can be loading um like
a neural network behind it and it will
totally work so
there you go I hope you found it useful
I hope that you learned a lot and be
sure to subscribe for more videos like
this and be sure to leave a like and
don't forget to write a comment as well
if you liked it and to tell me if you
had any questions also if you have if
you find a comment that you know the
answer to of someone I mean if someone
if you see someone asking a question and
you know the answer to that question
don't hesitate to to answer it's a good
way to to to learn when you explain uh
what is going on uh so thank you very
much again for watching and I will see
you in the next one
[Music]
thank you